Graf, Oskar Marie; Papers ger002
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria Graf, 1919-1967; 4; 378 file folders
  - Published novels, short story collections, 1919-1989; 4.1
    - An manchen Tagen: "Betrachtung über George Washington" (p. 344), Undated; typescript (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 29)
    - An manchen Tagen: "Das sinnvollste Beispiel" or "Die Mutter" (p. 364), Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 30)
    - An manchen Tagen: "Vom Sinn der Geschichte", Undated; typescript (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 31)
    - Anton Sittinger, 1937 (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 32)
      Typescript, exposé.
    - Anton Sittinger, Undated (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 33)
    - Anton Sittinger. Photos from the 1979 television film, Undated (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 34)
    - Anton Sittinger .Radio play adaptation by Edmund Steinberger. Part I., Undated (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 35)
    - Anton Sittinger .Radio play adaptation by Edmund Steinberger. Part I., Undated (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 36)
    - Banscho oder Die Freiheit, 1983; photocopy of typescript (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 37)
    - Banscho oder Die Freiheit, Undated; photocopy of typescript, continued (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 38)
    - Banscho oder Die Freiheit / Banscho or The Fight for Freedom, Undated (Box 4 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 39)
      Exposés, review.
    - Das bayrische Dekameron (1928): "Der ungewöhnliche Zeuge" (p. 234), Undated; manuscript, clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 1)
    - Das bayrische Dekameron: "Das Ausprobieren oder die Katz kauft man nicht im Sack", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 2)
    - Das bayrische Dekameron, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 3)
      Exposé, reviews.
    - Bayrische Dorfgeschichten aus früheren und heutigen Zeiten (1979), Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 4)
      Review.
    - Bayrisches Lesebücherl, 1930 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 5)
    - Exposés, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 6)
      Bolwieser (1931) / Die Ehe des Herrn Bolwieser (1977).
    - Bolwieser / Die Ehe des Herrn Bolwieser, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 7)
      Reviews of the book.
    - Bolwieser, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 8)
      Reviews of the film adaptation by Rainer Werner Fassbinder.
    - Bolwieser. Photographs from the movie, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 9)
    - The Stationmaster's Wife. English translation of Bolwieser, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 10)
    - Kleinstadt-Ballade. Play adaptation of Bolwieser by Graf and Walter Kiewert, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 11)
      Photocopy of playscript.
    - Die Chronik von Flechting, 1925; bound typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 12)
    - Die Chronik von Flechting, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 13)
    - Dorfbanditen (1927): "Der Überfall am Red River" (p. 44), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 14)
    - Dorfbanditen: "Wie wir den damischen Mischer losgebracht haben" (p. 117), Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 15)
    - Einer gegen alle, 1932 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 16)
    - The Wolf. English translation of Einer gegen alle, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 17)
      Photocopy of text, reviews.
    - Die Erben des Untergangs / Die Eroberung der Welt, 1949 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 18)
      Exposés, reviews.
    - Der ewige Kalendar (1954). Original artwork for the book by Amy Jauss; certificate of registration, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 19)
    - Die Flucht ins Mittelmässige (1959): "Der Herr mit dem seidenen Halstuch" (p. 32), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 20)
    - Die Flucht ins Mittelmässige: "Die missglückte Pietät" (p. 206), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 21)
    - Die Flucht ins Mittelmässige / The Flight into Mediocrity, Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 22)
    - Frühzeit, 1920; photocopy of typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 23)
    - Gelächter von Aussen, 1966 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 24)
    - Gelächter von Aussen, 1966 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 25)
    - Die gezählten Jahre, 1936 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 26)
    - "David gegen Goliath oder Stärker als Hitler". Film adaptation of the novel Die gezählten Jahre, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 27)
    - Grösstenteils schimpflich, 1962 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 28)
    - Grösstenteils schimpflich: "Das Gedicht", Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 29)
    - Der grosse Bauernspiegel, 1962 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 30)
    - Der grosse Bauernspiegel: "Das Moor" (p. 9), Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 31)
    - Der grosse Bauernspiegel: "Doktor Joseph Leiberer seligen Angedenkens" (p. 165), Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 32)
    - Der grosse Bauernspiegel: "Wie die Kohlhäuslertraudl kuriert" (p. 217), Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 33)
    - Der grosse Bauernspiegel: "Der Held" (p. 233), Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 34)
    - Der harte Handel, 1935 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 35)
    - Die Heimsuchung, 1927 (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 36)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten. Introduction by Oskar Maria Graf and editor, dated 1964; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 37)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Das Kaiserbild" (p. 13), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 38)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Ein barockes Malerporträt" (p. 25), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 39)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Ein Dichter wider Willen" (p. 64), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 40)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Aus unbekannten Motiven" (p. 73), Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 41)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Die Versuchung des Franz Perlbeck" (p. 78), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 42)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Spuk im Hinterhof" (p. 91), Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 43)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Der Quasterl" (p. 95), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 44)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "'Lasset die Kindlein zu mir kommen ...' Eine Waisenhausgeschichte" (p. 132), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 45)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Ein Sohn Davids" (p. 142), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 46)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Ein Sohn Davids" / "A Son of David" (p. 142), Undated (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 47)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Die Weihnachtsgans" (p. 153), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 48)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Die gebrechlichen Grundsaetze" (p. 160), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 49)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Die Rache des Verschmaehten" / "'Fuchsi' und das Kind" (p. 169), Undated; typescripts, clippings (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 50)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Was ist Glück?" (p. 178), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 51)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Der unentwegte Zivilist" (p. 190), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 52)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Der Kranz oder das Bitterste" (p. 202), Undated; clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 53)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Der Lehrer Maenner" (p. 209), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 54)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Nur ein Stückchen Schokolade" (p. 244), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 55)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Der Ueberfall" (p. 256), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 56)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Die Lunge" (p. 260), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 57)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Niemand kann allein sein" (p. 262), Undated; typescripts, pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 58)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Der Mord aus Zufall" (p. 273), Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 59)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Sporer" (p. 281), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 60)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Schlaflosigkeit" (p. 296), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 61)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Was bleibt" (p. 305), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 62)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Kalt" (p. 327), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 63)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Ein dummer Mensch" (p. 333), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 64)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Zwischenakt um 1919" (p. 346), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 65)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Ursula Peschl" (p. 356), Undated; typescripts, pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 66)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Vergebliche Vergeltung" (p. 365), Undated; typescripts (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 67)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Dreimal ist einmal" (p. 381), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 68)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Angst" (p. 411), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 69)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Angst" / "Fear". English translation, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 70)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Dreimalige Mahnung" (p. 425), Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 71)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Wahrer Patriotismus" (p. 435), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 72)
    - Jedermanns Geschichten: "Einer fuer alle" (p. 453), Undated; typescript (Box 5 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 73)
    - Kalendergeschichten, 1929; 1975 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 1)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Das Aderlassen. Ein Bauerngeschichte" (p. 68), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 2)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Das unrechte Geld" (p. 88), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 3)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Das Fuchseisen" (p. 104), Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 4)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der Spaziertrunk" (p. 110), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 5)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Das Hochzeitsgeschenk" (p. 148), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 6)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Die billige Watschn" (p. 184), Undated; page proofs (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 7)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Des Pudels Kern" (p. 206), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 8)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der letzte Mensch will heiraten" (p. 210), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 9)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Ein Denkmal für mein Basl Marei" (p. 222), Undated; clippings (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 10)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der missglückte Einbruch" (p. 233), Undated; clippings (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 11)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der Hängstrick" (p. 238), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 12)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Die Liebe bringt es an den Tag" / "Der geführliche Liebhaber" (p. 284), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 13)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der Schmalzerhans. Eine unvergessliche altbayrische Figur" (p. 295), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 14)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der unueberwindliche Kaslmeier" (p. 319), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 15)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Auffassung freibleibend" (p. 368), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 16)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Der Omauf" (p. 385), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 17)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Die Siedler" (p. 422), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 18)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Die Episode von Tragelberg" (p. 501), Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 19)
    - Kalendergeschichten: "Die Kruemelin" (p. 510), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 20)
    - Das Leben meiner Mutter, 1946 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 21)
    - Das Leben meiner Mutter / The Life of My Mother, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 22)
    - Mitmenschen, 1959 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 23)
      Exposé, photocopied pages from the novel.
    - Notizbuch des Provinzschriftstellers Oskar Maria Graf, 1932; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 24)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil. Ed. by Helmut Pfanner, 1989 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 25)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Nicht gehaltene Rede" (p. 24), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 26)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Dachauer Chronik" (p. 34), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 27)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Bayerische Dämmerung von einem Menschen" (p. 38), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 28)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Kleine Erinnerungen an Boris Pasternak" (p. 47), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 29)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Einführung von Sergei Tretjakow" (p. 52), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 30)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Einführung von Ilja Ehrenburg" (p. 55), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 31)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Im memoriam Felix Fechenbach" (p. 66), Undated; typescripts, clippings (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 32)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Einführung von Klaus Mann" (p. 82), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 33)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Rede über sich selbst und Deutschland" (p. 86), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 34)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Für John Heartfield" (p. 109), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 35)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Einführung von Ernst Toller" (p. 115), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 36)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Für die Demokratie!" (p. 119), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 37)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Rede zum Deutschen Tag" (p. 135), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 38)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Rede aus dem Mitgliedversammlung der GAWA" (p. 141), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 39)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Die Juden stehen nicht allein" (p. 154), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 40)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Das deutsche Volk und Hitlers Krieg" (p. 200), Undated; typescript (pc.), clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 41)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Roda Roda zum Gedenken" (p. 236), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 42)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Nekrolog für einen Freund" (p. 347), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 43)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Arabeske ueber den phantasievollen Menschen" (p. 368), Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 44)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Erregung, Abwehr und Urteile" (p. 372), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 45)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Was mich abhält nach Deutschland zurückzukehren" (p. 375), Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 46)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Die Sexualdemokratie" (p. 381), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 47)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Über Gruppe 47" (p. 406), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 48)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Aphorismen" (p. 409), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 49)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Rückblick" (p. 420), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 50)
    - Reden und Aufsätze aus dem Exil: "Zurück zur Sentimentalität" (p. 421), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 51)
    - Reise in die Sowjetunion, 1934 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 52)
    - Der Triumph der Gerechten. Table of contents, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 53)
    - Ua-Pua...! (Indianer-Dichtungen), 1921 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 54)
    - Unruhe um einen Friedfertigen, 1947 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 55)
    - Wir sind Gefangene, 1927 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 56)
    - Wir sind Gefangene: "Die Rebellion" (p. 444), Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 57)
    - Wir sind Gefangene / Prisoners All, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 58)
    - Wir sind Gefangene / Nous sommes prisonniers. Pc. of French translation, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 59)
    - Wir sind Gefangene. Historical background material, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 60)
    - Wunderbare Menschen, 1927; bound typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 61)
    - Wunderbare Menschen, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 62)
    - Short exposés of novels, Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 63)
  - Unpublished novels, 1913-1935; Undated; 4.2
    - "Das Testament des Kaspar Heinrath. Die Geschichte einer grossen Liebe", 1913; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 64)
    - "Der in Verwirrung geratene Zivilist", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 65)
    - "Der Moralist", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 66)
    - "Dusk, Darkness, Dawn", Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 67)
      Synopsis.
    - "Geliebte Johanna", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 68)
    - "Geliebte Johanna" / "Jane! ... Beloved Jane! ...", Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 69)
      Synopsis in English.
    - "Menschen aus einer anderen Welt oder Das Testament des Malers Joseph Lechner", 1939; bound typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 70)